Nants ingonyama
Bagithi baba
Sithi uhhmm ingonyama
lngonyama
Nants ingonyama
Bagithi baba
Sithi uhhmm ingonyama
lngonyama
Siyo nqoba
lngonyama inengw' enamabala
Setokwa
Asana
lngonyama inengw' enamabala
Setokwa
From the day we arrive
On the planet
And, blinking, step into the sun
There's more to see
Than can ever be seen
More to do
Than can ever be done
There's far too much
To take in here
More to find
Than can ever be found
But the sun rolling high
Through the sapphire sky
Keeps great and small
On the endless round
It's the circle of life
And it moves us all
Through despair and hope
Through faith and love
Till we find our place
On the path unwinding
In the circle
The circle of life
It's the circle of life
And it moves us all
Through despair and hope
Through faith and love
Till we find our place
On the path unwinding
In the circle
The circle of life
Life's not fair, is it?
You see, I   Well, I shall never be king
And you shall never see the light of another day
Didn't your mother ever tell you not to play with your food?
What do you want?
I'm here to announce that King Mufasa's on his way,
so you'd better have a good excuse for missing this morning's ceremony
Oh, look, Zazu
You've made me lose my lunch
You'll lose more than that when the king gets through with you
He's as mad as a hippo with a hernia
I quiver with fear!
Now, Scar, don't look at me that way
Help!
Scar?
Drop him
Impeccable timing, Your Majesty
Why, if it isn't my big brother descending from on high
to mingle with the commoners
Sarabi and I didn't see you at the presentation of Simba
That was today?
I feel simply awful !
Must've slipped my mind
Yes, well, as slippery as your mind is,
as the king's brother, you should've been first in line!
Well, I was first in line, until the little hairball was born
That hairball is my son and your future king
I shall practise my curtsy!
Don't turn your back on me, Scar
Oh, no, Mufasa
Perhaps you shouldn't turn your back on me
Is that a challenge?
Temper, temper
I wouldn't dream of challenging you
Pity Why not?
Well, as far as brains go, I got the lion's share
But when it comes to brute strength,
I'm afraid I'm at the shallow end of the gene pool
There's one in every family, sire
Two in mine, actually,
and they always manage to ruin special occasions
What am I going to do with him?
He'd make a very handsome throw rug
Zazu !
And just think, whenever he gets dirty,
you could take him out and beat him
Simba
Dad ! Dad !
Come on, dad, we gotta go! Wake up!
Sorry
Dad ! Dad !
Your son is awake
Before sunrise, he's your son
Dad ! Come on, Dad
You promised
Okay, Okay I'm up, I'm up
Yeah !
Look, Simba
Everything the light touches is our kingdom
Wow
A king's time as ruler rises and falls like the sun
One day, Simba, the sun will set on my time here
and will rise with you as the new king
And this'll all be mine? Everything
Everything the light touches
What about that shadowy place?
That's beyond our borders
You must never go there, Simba
But I thought a king can do whatever he wants
Oh, there's more to being king than getting your way all the time
There's more? Simba
Everything you see exists together in a delicate balance
As king, you need to understand that balance
and respect all the creatures,
from the crawling ant to the leaping antelope
But, Dad, don't we eat the antelope?
Yes, Simba, but let me explain
When we die, our bodies become the grass,
and the antelope eat the grass
And so we are all connected in the great circle of life
Good morning, sire! Good morning, Zazu
Checking in with the morning report
Fire away
Well ! The buzz from the bees
is that the leopards are in a bit of a spot
Really?
What are you doing, son?
Pouncing
Let an old pro show you how it's done
I told the elephants to forget it, but they can't
Zazu, would you turn around? Yes, sire
The cheetahs are hard up, but
Stay low to the ground
Cheetahs never prosper
Yeah, okay Stay low to the ground, right? Yeah
What going on? A pouncing lesson
Very good Pouncing
Pouncing? No, sire, you can't be serious
This is so humiliating
Try not to make a sound
What are you telling him, Mufasa?
Mufasa? Simba?
That's very good
Zazu ! Yes!
News from the underground Now, this time
Sire! Hyenas in the Pride Lands!
Zazu, take Simba home
Dad, can't I come?
No, son
I never get to go anywhere
Young master, one day, you will be king
Then you can chase those slobbering, mangy, stupid poachers
from dawn until dusk
Hey, Uncle Scar! Guess what?
I despise guessing games
I'm gonna be King of Pride Rock
Oh, goody!
My dad just showed me the whole kingdom,
and I'm gonna rule it all !
Yes Well, forgive me for not leaping for joy
Bad back, you know
Hey, Uncle Scar
When I'm king, what'll that make you?
A monkey's uncle
You're so weird You have no idea
So, your father showed you the whole kingdom, did he?
Everything
He didn't show you what's beyond that rise at the northern border?
Well, no He said I can't go there
And he's absolutely right
It's far too dangerous
Only the bravest lions go there
Well, I'm brave What's out there?
I'm sorry, Simba, I just can't tell you
Why not?
I'm only looking out for the wellbeing of my favourite nephew
Yeah, right! I'm your only nephew
All the more reason for me to be protective
An elephant graveyard is no place for a young prince Oops!
An elephant what? Whoa!
Oh, dear, I've said too much
Well, I suppose you'd have found out sooner or later,
you being so clever and all
Just do me one favour
Promise me you'll never visit that dreadful place
No problem
There's a good lad
You run along now and have fun
And remember,
it's our little secret
Hey, Nala Hi, Simba
Come on I just heard about this great place
Simba! I'm kind of in the middle of a bath
And it's time for yours
Mom !
Mom, you're messing up my mane!
Okay, okay, I'm clean Can we go now?
So, where are we going?
It better not be anyplace dumb
No, it's really cool
So, where is this really cool place?
Around the water hole The water hole?
What's so great about the water hole?
I'll show you when we get there
Mom, can I go with Simba?
What do you think, Sarabi?
Well
Please? Please?
It's all right with me
Yeah ! All right!
As long as Zazu goes with you
No, not Zazu
Step lively
The sooner we get to the water hole, the sooner we can leave
So, where are we really going?
An elephant graveyard
Wow!
Zazu
Right So, how are we gonna ditch the dodo?
Just look at you two
Little seeds of romance blossoming in the savanna
Your parents will be thrilled,
what with your being betrothed and all
Bewhat?
Betrothed Intended
Affianced
Meaning
One day, you two are going to be married
Yuck!
I can't marry her She's my friend
Yeah, it'd be so weird
Sorry to bust your bubble,
but you two turtle doves have no choice
It's a tradition going back generations
When I'm king, that'll be the first thing to go
Not so long as I'm around Well, in that case, you're fired
Nice try, but only the king can do that
Well, he's the future king
Yeah, so you have to do what I tell you
Not yet, I don't
And with an attitude like that,
I'm afraid you're shaping up to be a pretty pathetic king, indeed
Not the way I see it
l'm gonna be a mighty king
So enemies beware
Well, l've never seen a king of beasts
With quite so little hair
l'm gonna be the main event
Like no king was before
l'm brushin' up on lookin' down
l'm workin' on my roar
Thus far, a rather uninspiring thing
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
You've rather a long way to go, young master, if you think
No one sayin', "Do this" Now, when l said that
No one saying, "Be there" What I meant was
No one sayin', "Stop that" You don't realise
No one sayin', "See here" Now, see here!
Free to run around all day
Well, that's definitely out
Free to do it all my way
l think it's time that you and l
Arranged a hearttoheart
Kings don't need advice
From little hornbills for a start
If this is where the monarchy is headed
Count me out
Out of service, out of Africa
l wouldn't hang about
This child is getting wildly out of wing
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
Everybody, look left
Everybody, look right
Everywhere you look, l'm
Standing in the spotlight
Not yet!
Let every creature go for broke and sing
Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing
lt's gonna be King Simba's finest fling
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
Oh, I just can't wait
To be king
I beg your pardon, madam, but
get off!
Simba?
Nala!
All right! It worked !
We lost him I am a genius
Hey, genius, it was my idea
Yeah, but I pulled it off
With me! Yeah?
Pinned ya Hey, let me up!
Pinned ya again
This is it We made it
Whoa!
It's really creepy
Yeah
Isn't it great?
We could get in big trouble I know!
I wonder if its brains are still in there
There's only one way to know
Come on, let's go check it out
Wrong ! The only checking out you will do will be to check out of here
Oh, man !
We're way beyond the boundary of the Pride Lands
Look, banana beak is scared
It's Mr banana beak to you, fuzzy,
and right now we are all in very real danger
Danger?
I walk on the wild side
I laugh in the face of danger
Well, well, well, Banzai, what have we got here?
I don't know, Shenzi
What do you think, Ed?
Just what I was thinking
A trio of trespassers!
And quite by accident, let me assure you
A simple navigational error
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait
I know you You're Mufasa's little stooge
I, madam, am the king's majordomo
And that would make you
The future king
Do you know what we do to kings who step out of their kingdom?
You can't do anything to me
Technically, they can We are on their land
But you told me they're nothing but slobbering, mangy, stupid poachers
Ixnay on the upidstay
Who are you callin' upidstay? My, my, my Look at the sun !
It's time to go! What's the hurry?
We'd love you to stick around for dinner
Yeah, we could have whatever's lion around !
Wait, wait, wait, I got one, I got one!
Make mine a cub sandwich ! Whaddaya think?
What, Ed? What is it?
Hey, did we order this dinner to go?
No, why?
'Cause there it goes!
Did we lose 'em? I think so
Where's Zazu?
The little majordomo bird hippetyhopped
all the way to the birdieboiler
No! Not the birdieboiler!
Hey, why don't you pick on somebody your own size?
Like you? Oops
Boo!
Simba!
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty
That was it?
Do it again Come on
Please, please! Uncle, uncle! Silence!
We're gonna shut up right now! Calm down We're really sorry
If you ever come near my son again
This is   This is your son?
Your son Did you know that?
No Me? I didn't know   No, did you?
No, of course not No
Ed?
Toodles
Dad, I You deliberately disobeyed me
Dad, I'm   I'm sorry Let's go home
I thought you were very brave
Zazu
Yes, sire?
Take Nala home I've got to teach my son a lesson
Come, Nala
Simba, good luck
Simba!
Simba, I'm very disappointed in you
I know You could've been killed
You deliberately disobeyed me,
and what's worse, you put Nala in danger
I was just trying to be brave, like you
I'm only brave when I have to be
Simba, being brave
doesn't mean you go looking for trouble
But you're not scared of anything
I was today
You were? Yes
I thought I might lose you
I guess even kings get scared, huh?
But you know what? What?
I think those hyenas were even scareder
'Cause nobody messes with your dad
Come here, you No! No!
Come here!
Gotcha!
Dad?
We're pals, right? Right
And we'll always be together, right?
Simba, let me tell you something that my father told me
Look at the stars
The great kings of the past look down on us from those stars
Really? Yes
So whenever you feel alone,
just remember that those kings will always be there to guide you
And so will I
Man, that lousy Mufasa I won't be able to sit for a week
It's not funny, Ed
Hey, shut up!
Will you knock it off?
Well, he started it Look at you guys
No wonder we're dangling at the bottom of the food chain
Man, I hate dangling
Yeah? If it weren't for those lions, we'd be runnin' the joint
Man, I hate lions
So pushy And hairy
And stinky And, man, are they
Ugly!
Surely we lions are not all that bad
Scar It's just you
We were afraid it was somebody important
Yeah, you know, like Mufasa
Yeah I see
Now that's power! Tell me about it
I just hear that name and I shudder
Mufasa! Do it again
Mufasa!
Mufasa! Mufasa! Mufasa!
It tingles me
I'm surrounded by idiots
Now, you, Scar, I mean, you're one of us I mean, you're our pal
Charmed
I like that He's not king, but he's still so proper
Yeah Hey, did you bring us anything to eat,
Scar, old buddy, old pal? Huh? Did ya, did ya, did ya?
I don't think you really deserve this
I practically giftwrapped those cubs for you,
and you couldn't even dispose of them
Well, you know, it wasn't exactly like they was alone, Scar
Yeah What were we supposed to do?
Kill Mufasa?
Precisely
l know that your powers of retention
Are as wet as a warthog's backside
But thick as you are, pay attention
My words are a matter of pride
lt's clear from your vacant expressions
The lights are not all on upstairs
But we're talking kings and successions
Even you can't be caught unawares
So prepare for the chance of a lifetime
Be prepared for sensational news
A shiny new era is tiptoeing nearer
And where do we feature?
Just listen to teacher
I know it sounds sordid
But you'll be rewarded
When at last l am given my dues
And injustice deliciously squared
Be prepared
Yeah, be prepared We'll be prepared For what?
For the death of the king
Why, is he sick? No, fool, we're going to kill him
And Simba, too Great idea Who needs a king?
No king, no king
Idiots! There will be a king ! Hey, but you said
I will be king !
Stick with me,
and you'll never go hungry again
Yeah ! All right! Long live the king !
Long live the king ! Long live the king !
lt's great that we'll soon be connected
With a king who'll be alltime adored
Of course, quid pro quo you're expected
To take certain duties on board
The future is littered with prizes
And though l'm the main addressee
The point that l must emphasise is
You won't get a sniff without me!
So prepare for the coup of the century
Be prepared for the murkiest scam
Meticulous planning
Tenacity spanning
Decades of denial
ls simply why l'll be king undisputed
Respected, saluted
And seen for the wonder I am
Yes, my teeth and ambitions are bared
Be prepared
Yes, our teeth and ambitions are bared
You wait here Your father has a marvellous surprise for you
What is it?
If I told you, it wouldn't be a surprise now, would it?
If you tell me, I'll still act surprised
You are such a naughty boy
Come on, Uncle Scar No, no, no, no, no, no, no
This is just for you and your daddy
You know, a sort of fatherson thing
Well, I'd better go get him
I'll go with you No
No Just stay on this rock
You wouldn't want to end up in another mess
like you did with the hyenas
You know about that? Simba, everybody knows about that
Really? Yes
Lucky daddy was there to save you, eh?
And just between us,
you might want to work on that little roar of yours, hmm?
Okay
Hey, Uncle Scar, will I like this surprise?
Simba, it's to die for
Shut up
I can't help it I'm so hungry I got to have a wildebeest
Stay put
Can't I just pick off one of the little sick ones?
No We wait for the signal from Scar
There he is Let's go
"Little roar"
Look, sire, the herd is on the move
Odd Mufasa, quick
Stampede in the gorge
Simba's down there! Simba?
Zazu, help me!
Your father is on the way! Hold on !
Hurry!
There! There on that tree!
Hold on, Simba!
Dad !
Scar, this is awful !
What'll we do? What'll we do?
I'll go back for help, that's what I'll do
Dad !
Scar!
Brother Brother, help me!
Long live the king
No!
Dad !
Dad?
Dad, come on
You got to get up
Dad?
We got to go home
Help!
Somebody!
Anybody
Help
Simba What have you done?
There were wildebeests, and he tried to save me
It was an accident I didn't mean for it to happen
Of course Of course you didn't
No one ever means for these things to happen
But the king is dead
And if it weren't for you, he'd still be alive
What will your mother think?
What am I going to do?
Run away, Simba
Run Run away and never return
Kill him
Whoa!
Hey, there he goes There he goes
So go get him
There ain't no way I'm going in there
What, you want me to come out looking like you, cactus butt?
But we got to finish the job
Well, he's as good as dead out there anyway
And if he comes back, we'll kill him
Yeah ! You hear that?
If you ever come back, we'll kill you !
Mufasa's death is a terrible tragedy
But to lose Simba, who had barely begun to live
For me, it is a deep, personal loss
So it is with a heavy heart that I assume the throne
Yet out of the ashes of this tragedy we shall rise
to greet the dawning of a new era
in which lion and hyena come together
in a great and glorious future
Get out! Get out! Get out of here!
I love this! Bowling for buzzards
Gets 'em every time
Hey, Timon, you better come look
I think it's still alive
All righty, what have we got here?
Jeez, it's a lion ! Run, Pumbaa, move it!
Hey, Timon, it's just a little lion
Look at him He's so cute and all alone
Can we keep him? Pumbaa, are you nuts?
You're talking about a lion Lions eat guys like us
But he's so little He's going to get bigger
Maybe he'll be on our side
That's the stupidest thing I ever heard Maybe he'll
Hey, I've got it What if he's on our side?
You know, having a lion around might not be such a bad idea
So we're keeping him?
Of course Who's the brains of this outfit?
My point exactly
Jeez, I'm fried Let's get out of here and find some shade
You okay, kid? I guess so
You nearly died
I saved you
Well, Pumbaa helped A little
Thanks for your help
Hey, where you going?
Nowhere
Gee, he looks blue
I'd say brownish gold No, no, no I mean he's depressed
Kid, what's eating you?
Nothing He's at the top of the food chain
The food chain !
So, where you from?
Who cares? I can't go back
You're an outcast That's great So are we
What'd you do, kid? Something terrible
But I don't want to talk about it We don't want to hear about it
Come on, Timon Anything we can do?
Not unless you can change the past
You know, kid, in times like this, my buddy Timon here says,
"You got to put your behind in your past"
No, no, no
I mean Amateur
Lie down before you hurt yourself
It's, "You got to put your past behind you"
Look, kid, bad things happen, and you can't do anything about it, right?
Right Wrong !
When the world turns its back on you,
you turn your back on the world
Well, that's not what I was taught
Then maybe you need a new lesson
Repeat after me
Hakuna matata What?
Hakuna matata
It means "no worries"
What a wonderful phrase
Hakuna matata
Ain't no passing craze
It means no worries
For the rest of your days
lt's our problemfree philosophy
Hakuna matata
Hakuna matata?
Yeah It's our motto What's a motto?
Nothin' What'samotto with you?
You know, kid, these two words will solve all your problems
That's right Take Pumbaa, for example Why
When he was a young warthog
When l was a young warthog
Very nice Thanks
He found his aroma lacked a certain appeal
He could clear the savanna after every meal
I'm a sensitive soul
Though l seem thickskinned
And it hurt that my friends never stood downwind
And, oh, the shame He was ashamed
Thought of changing my name Oh, what's in a name?
And l got downhearted
How did you feel? Every time that l
Hey, not in front of the kids Oh, sorry
Hakuna matata
What a wonderful phrase
Ain't no passing craze
It means no worries
For the rest of your days
Yeah, sing it, kid
lt's our problemfree
Philosophy
Hakuna matata
Welcome to our humble home
You live here? We live wherever we want
Yep Home is where your rump rests
It's beautiful
I'm starved
I'm so hungry I could eat a whole zebra
We're fresh out of zebra
Any antelope?
Hippo? Nope
Listen, kid, if you live with us, you have to eat like us
Hey, this looks like a good spot to rustle up some grub
What's that?
A grub What's it look like?
Gross
Tastes like chicken
Slimy yet satisfying
These are rare delicacies
Piquant, with a very pleasant crunch
You'll learn to love them
I'm telling you, kid, this is the great life,
no rules, no responsibilities
The little creamfilled kind
And best of all, no worries
Well, kid?
Oh, well Hakuna matata
Slimy, yet satisfying
That's it
Hakuna matata
Hakuna It means no worries
For the rest of your days
lt's our problemfree
Philosophy
Hakuna matata
Yeah
Tata!
Nobody knows
The trouble I've seen
My sorrow
Zazu, do lighten up
Sing something with a little bounce in it
It's a small world after all
No, no! Anything but that!
l've got a lovely bunch of coconuts
Deedle dee dee
There they are astanding in a row
Big ones, small ones, some as big as your head
I would never have had to do this with Mufasa
What? What did you say?
Nothing You know the law
Never, ever mention that name in my presence I am the king !
Yes, sire, you are the king
I   I only mentioned it to illustrate the differences
in your royal managerial approaches
Hey, boss What is it this time?
We got a bone to pick with you I'll handle this
Scar, there's no food, no water
Yeah It's dinner time and we ain't got no stinking entrées
It's the lionesses' job to do the hunting
Yeah, but they won't go hunt
Eat Zazu You wouldn't want me
I'd be so tough and gamey and
Zazu, don't be ridiculous All you need is a little garlic
I thought things were bad under Mufasa
What did you say? I said Muf
I said qué pasa?
Good Now get out
But we're still hungry
Out!
Whoa! Nice one, Simba Thanks
Man, I'm stuffed Me, too
I ate like a pig
Pumbaa, you are a pig
Right
Timon? Yeah?
Ever wonder what those sparkling dots are up there?
Pumbaa, I don't wonder, I know
What are they?
They're fireflies
Fireflies that got stuck up in that big bluishblack thing
Gee
I always thought they were balls of gas
burning billions of miles away
Pumbaa, with you, everything's gas
Simba, what do you think?
Well, I don't know
Come on Give, give, give, give
Come on We told you ours Please?
Well
Somebody once told me
that the great kings of the past are up there watching over us
Really?
You mean a bunch of royal dead guys are watching us?
Who told you something like that? Yeah, yeah
What mook made that up? Yeah Pretty dumb, huh?
You're killing me Yeah
Was it something I said?
Simba?
He's   He's alive? He's alive!
It is time
Awimoweh, awimoweh
ln the jungle, the mighty jungle
The lion sleeps tonight
The lion sleeps to
I can't hear you, buddy Back me up
APumbaabumbaaweh
Pumbaa? Pumbaa?
Timon?
Pumbaa?
Pumbaa! Pumbaa!
Pumbaa, Pumbaa! Hey, what's going on?
She's going to eat me!
Whoa! Jeez, why do I always have to save your
Don't worry, buddy I'm here for you Everything's going to be okay
Get her! Bite her head !
Go for the jugular! The jugular!
See, I told you he'd come in handy
Nala?
Is it really you?
Who are you? It's me Simba
Simba?
Whoa! How did you
Wow! Where did you come from?
This is gr   It's great to see you !
Hey, what's goin' on here? What are you doing here?
What am I doing here? What are you doing here?
Hey! What's goin' on here?
Timon, this is Nala She's my best friend
Friend? Yeah Hey, Pumbaa, come over here
Nala, this is Pumbaa Pumbaa, Nala
Pleased to make your acquaintance The pleasure is all mine
How do you   Whoa, whoa! Time out! Let me get this straight
You know her, she knows you
But she wants to eat him, and everybody's okay with this?
Did I miss something? Relax, Timon
Wait till everyone finds out you've been here all this time
And your mother, what will she think?
She doesn't have to know Nobody has to know
Of course they do Everyone thinks you're dead
They do?
Yeah Scar told us about the stampede
He did? What else did he tell you?
What else matters? You're alive And that means, you're the king
King? Lady, have you got your lions crossed !
King?
Your Majesty, I gravel at your feet
Stop it It's not gravel, it's grovel
And don't! He's not the king Are you?
No Simba!
No, I'm not the king Maybe I was gonna be,
but that was a long time ago
Let me get this straight You're the king? And never told us?
Look, I'm still the same guy But with power
Could you guys excuse us for a few minutes?
Hey, whatever she has to say,
she can say in front of us, right, Simba?
Maybe you'd better go
It starts You think you know a guy
Timon and Pumbaa, you learn to love 'em
What?
What is it?
It's like you're back from the dead
You don't know how much this will mean to everyone
What it means to me
Hey, it's okay I've really missed you
I've missed you, too
I tell you, Pumbaa This stinks
Sorry
Not you ! Them !
Him, her, alone
What's wrong with that?
l can see what's happening What?
And they don't have a clue Who?
They'll fall in love and here's the bottom line
Our trio's down to two
The sweet caress of twilight
There's magic everywhere
And with all this romantic atmosphere
Disaster's in the air
Can you feel the love tonight?
The peace the evening brings
The world for once
ln perfect harmony
With all its living things
So many things to tell her
But how to make her see
The truth about my past?
lmpossible, she'd turn away from me
He's holding back, he's hiding
But what, l can't decide
Why won't he be the king l know he is?
The king l see inside?
Can you feel the love tonight?
The peace the evening brings
The world for once
ln perfect harmony
With all its living things
Can you feel the love tonight?
You needn't look too far
Stealing through
The night's uncertainties
Love is where they are
And if he falls in love tonight
It can be assumed
His carefree days
With us are history
ln short, our pal
Is doomed
Isn't this a great place?
It is beautiful
But I don't understand something
You've been alive all this time
Why didn't you come back to Pride Rock?
Well, I just needed to get out on my own, live my own life
And I did, and it's great
We've really needed you at home
No one needs me Yes, we do You're the king
Nala, we've been through this I'm not the king Scar is
Simba, he let the hyenas take over the Pride Lands
What? Everything's destroyed
There's no food, no water
Simba, if you don't do something soon, everyone will starve
I can't go back Why?
You wouldn't understand What?
No, no, no It doesn't matter Hakuna matata
What? Hakuna matata
It's something I learned out here Sometimes bad things happen
Simba
and there's nothing you can do about it So why worry?
Because it's your responsibility Well, what about you? You left
I left to find help, and I found you
Don't you understand? You're our only hope
Sorry What's happened to you?
You're not the Simba I remember You're right I'm not
Now are you satisfied? No Just disappointed
You know, you're starting to sound like my father
Good At least one of us does
You think you can just show up and tell me how to live my life?
You don't even know what I've been through
I would if you'd just tell me
Forget it! Fine!
She's wrong I can't go back
What would it prove, anyway? It won't change anything
You can't change the past
You said you'd always be there for me!
But you're not
And it's because of me
It's my fault
Asante sana, squash banana
We we nugu, imi mi apana
Asante sana, squash banana We we nugu, imi mi apana
Come on, will you cut it out?
Can't cut it out It'll grow right back!
Creepy little monkey Will you stop following me?
Who are you? The question is, who are you?
I thought I knew Now I'm not so sure
Well, I know who you are Come here It's a secret
Asante sana, squash banana
Enough ! What is that supposed to mean?
It means you are a baboon, and I'm not
I think you're a little confused
Wrong ! I'm not the one who's confused
You don't even know who you are And I suppose you know
Sure do You're Mufasa's boy
Bye Hey, wait!
You knew my father?
Correction, I know your father
I hate to tell you this,
but he died a long time ago
Nope Wrong again !
He's alive, and I'll show him to you
You follow old Rafiki He knows the way Come on !
Don't dawdle Hurry up!
Hey, whoa, wait, wait Come on Come on !
Would you slow down?
Stop!
Look down there
That's not my father That's just my reflection
No
Look harder
You see?
He lives in you
Simba
Father?
Simba, you have forgotten me
No How could I?
You have forgotten who you are, and so have forgotten me
Look inside yourself, Simba
You are more than what you have become
You must take your place in the circle of life
How can I go back? I'm not who I used to be
Remember who you are
You are my son and the one true king
No! Please, don't leave me!
Remember
Father! Remember!
Don't leave me
Remember
What was that?
The weather
Very peculiar, don't you think? Yeah
Looks like the winds are changing
Change is good
Yeah, but it's not easy
I know what I have to do, but going back means I'll have to face my past
I've been running from it for so long
Jeez! What was that for?
It doesn't matter It's in the past
Yeah, but it still hurts
Yes, the past can hurt
But the way I see it you can either run from it
or learn from it
You see? So what are you going to do?
First, I'm gonna take your stick
No, no, no, no! Not the stick!
Hey! Where are you going? I'm going back!
Good ! Go on ! Get out of here!
Grubs! Grubs!
Hey Hey, wake up
It's okay! Whoa, whoa! It's okay! It's me!
Don't ever do that again
Carnivores!
Have you guys seen Simba? I thought he was with you
He was, but now I can't find him Where is he?
You won't find him here!
The king has returned
I can't believe it He's gone back!
Gone back? What do you mean?
Hey, what's goin' on here?
Who's the monkey? Simba went back to challenge Scar
Who? Scar
Who's got a scar? No, it's his uncle
The monkey's his uncle? No!
Simba's gone back to challenge his uncle to take his place as king
Simba, wait up!
It's awful, isn't it? I didn't want to believe you
What made you come back?
I finally got some sense knocked into me,
and I've got the bump to prove it
Besides, this is my kingdom
If I don't fight for it, who will?
I will It's gonna be dangerous
Danger? I laugh in the face of danger
I see nothing funny about this
Timon ! Pumbaa! What are you doing here?
At your service, my liege
We're gonna fight your uncle for this?
Yes, Timon This is my home
Talk about your fixerupper!
Well, Simba, if it's important to you, we're with you to the end
Hyenas I hate hyenas
So what's your plan for getting past those guys?
Live bait Good idea Hey!
Come on, Timon You guys have to create a diversion
What do you want me to do, dress in drag and do the hula?
Luau !
lf you're hungry for a hunk of fat and juicy meat
Eat my buddy Pumbaa here because he is a treat
Come on down and dine on this tasty swine
All you have to do is get in line
Are you achin' Yep, yep, yep
For some bacon? Yep, yep, yep
He's a big pig Yep, yep
You could be a big pig, too!
Nala, you find my mother and rally the lionesses
I'll look for Scar
Sarabi !
Yes, Scar?
Where is your hunting party? They're not doing their job
Scar, there is no food The herds have moved on
No, you're just not looking hard enough
It's over There is nothing left
We have only one choice We must leave Pride Rock
We're not going anywhere You have sentenced us to death
Then so be it You can't do that
I am the king I can do whatever I want
If you were half the king Mufasa was
I'm ten times the king Mufasa was!
Mufasa? No, you're dead
Mufasa?
No It's me
Simba! You're alive? How can that be?
It doesn't matter I'm home
Simba?
Simba! I'm a little surprised to see you
alive
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't rip you apart
Simba, you must understand
The pressures of ruling a kingdom
Are no longer yours Step down, Scar
Well, I would, naturally
However, there is one little problem
You see them?
They think I'm king
Well, we don't Simba's the rightful king
The choice is yours, Scar
Either step down or fight
Must this all end in violence?
I'd hate to be responsible for the death of a family member
Wouldn't you agree, Simba? That's not gonna work, Scar
I've put it behind me
But what about your faithful subjects?
Have they put it behind them?
Simba, what is he talking about?
So you haven't told them your little secret
Well, Simba, now's your chance to tell them
Tell them who is responsible for Mufasa's death
I am
It's not true
Tell me it's not true
It's true You see? He admits it!
Murderer! No! It was an accident
If it weren't for you, Mufasa would be alive It's your fault he's dead !
Do you deny it? No
Then you're guilty No, I'm not a murderer!
Simba, you're in trouble again,
but this time daddy isn't here to save you,
and now everyone knows why!
Simba!
Now, this looks familiar
Where have I seen this before? Let me think
Yes I remember
This is just the way your father looked before he died
And here's my little secret
I killed Mufasa
No! Murderer!
No, Simba, please Tell them the truth
Truth? But truth is in the eye of the behold
All right
I did it
So they can hear you
I killed Mufasa!
Excuse me Pardon me Comin' through Hot stuff
Let me out! Let me out! Let me in ! Let me in !
Please, don't eat me
Drop 'em !
Hey, who's the pig? Are you talkin' to me?
He called him a pig To me?
Shouldn't have done that To me?
Now they're in for it They call me Mr Pig !
Take that, you stupid
Take that and that!
Run, you yellowbelly!
Murderer Simba Simba, please
Please, have mercy I beg you You don't deserve to live
But Simba, I am family
It's the hyenas who are the real enemy
It was their fault It was their idea
Why should I believe you?
Everything you ever told me was a lie
What are you going to do?
You wouldn't kill your own uncle
No, Scar
I'm not like you
Simba, thank you You are truly noble
I'll make it up to you, I promise And how can I prove myself to you?
Tell me I mean, anything
Run
Run away, Scar,
and never return
Yes
Of course
As you wish,
your Majesty!
My friends!
Friends? I thought he said we were the enemy
Yeah That's what I heard
Ed?
No Let me explain No, you don't understand !
No, I didn't mean   No! No!
It is time
Remember
Sefile
Baba titabo
Maye babo busa ilomhlaba
Ubuse ngo xolo
Ubuse ngo thando
lngonyama inengw' enamabala
lngonyama nengw' enamabala
Till we find our place
On the path unwinding
In the circle
The circle of life
Circle of
Life